She was extraordinary.
Um, my mother taught me a lot about just
like
bringing intention to what you do.
Bringing sorry
and being the child of accomplished
parents. Most people thought that I
would lack the ambition, the
preparedness, but my mother taught me
that being underestimated is not a bad
thing. It's very powerful thing actually
and it almost always worked to the
detriment of the person who
underestimated me.
>> From real estate to her own
multi-million dollar fashion line,
Ivanka Trump continues to carve her own
path into the business world, succeeding
at every turn.
>> And then you learn 2 weeks before he
announces your father decides he wants
to be president of the United States.
Did you have any sense that this was at
all on the horizon?
>> Not really. And then when he pulled the
trigger, it was full steam. Well, most
people wouldn't give up an $800 million
annual business to go into government.
Why did you?
>> He asked us for help. He's like, "But I
have to warn you. They're going to come
at you hard. They're probably going to
hate you." But one of the things I've
learned in moments of tremendous
pressure and scrutiny where any slip up
is completely weaponized against you is
to find the signal in the noise. I just
don't get distracted by the outside
noise. That's probably the thing that
has been most helpful to me in terms of
performance and success because you have
a choice only in how you respond.
>> You've said politics is a pretty dark
world. This is quite a difficult
question to ask, but when you heard the
news that there was an assassination
attempt on your father's life, do you
remember where you were and like what's
that like as a daughter?
This is super interesting to me. My team
given me this report to show me how many
of you that watch this show subscribe.
And some of you have told us according
to this that you are unsubscribed from
the channel randomly. So favor to ask
all of you. Please could you check right
now if you've hit the subscribe button.
If you are a regular viewer of the show
and you like what we do here, we're
approaching quite a significant landmark
on this show in terms of a subscriber
number. So, if there was one simple free
thing that you could do to help us, my
team, everyone here, to keep this show
free, to keep it improving year over
year and week over week, it is just to
hit that subscribe button and to double
check if you've hit it. Only thing I'll
ever ask of you, do we have a deal? If
you do it, I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll make sure every single week, every
single month, we fight harder and harder
and harder and harder to bring you the
guests and conversations that you want
to hear. I've stayed true to that
promise since the very beginning of the
D of Sio, and I will not let you down.
Please help us. Really appreciate it.
Let's get on with the show.
>> Ivanka, you um you don't do many
interviews, do you?
>> Not really. No.
>> Why don't you do much media stuff or
podcasting or interviews?
>> I actually don't know. I think I'm I get
sort of really locked in and heads down
on what I'm working on
>> that
I tend to kind of put on blinders and
just go, but I like to have
conversations in longer form with people
that I admire.
>> I think the reason why I um I do this is
because I see I naturally see everybody
as like a jigsaw puzzle.
>> And you've lived an extraordinary life.
you've lived an extraordinary atypical
>> life that I mean it's safe to say almost
nobody on planet earth has has ever
experienced and so I think I asked that
question just to be completely honest at
the top because the life you've lived
that we'll get into is is one that would
have shaped you in a number of ways and
one of them is I think from what I read
things that you had said and different
experiences you had as a child is just
like trusting people
>> you know it's interesting I I grew up
the child of wealthy and accomplished
parents.
>> And so I do think there's like um a
natural barrier that goes up. You're
you're worried about people, especially
when you're a kid, um liking you for the
wrong reasons. I see this now with my
son. You know, he wants to be loved by
his friends, and I appreciate that.
That's that's good for who he is, not
for who we are, and certainly not for
what we have. So I do think being the
child of of of famous um parents and
living such a privileged life, I had
this
guard and um that guard served me really
well for a long time. Like I I didn't
have any friends despite the
really tumultuous
life that I've had, ups and downs, who
really disappointed me. meaning close
close close friends who who didn't show
up for me or or who changed because of
my circumstances or
>> what was happening around me and I've
learned for me I mean you were saying
the purpose of life for me it's you know
the expansion and not contraction of the
heart and that's hard as you get older
you know how do you live a life of of
service and rooted in and love and
connection and I've learned more and
more that those walls
they don't serve you and the only way to
have connection which is so fundamental
to the human experience is to um is to
build it and that requires trust.
>> So I have to trust people. Now I have a
good radar. I'm not foolish. I'm
>> I think I'm a very good read of people
and I think it's one of um my strengths
>> and I think it's why I haven't been
surprised by a lot of people. Um, so I
read pretty quickly, but I also have had
to teach myself rather than grow sort of
cynical as one tends to as they get
older. I've really actually taught
myself to be more trusting. And to the
extent that means periodically I'll be
burned like that's I'm okay with that
trade-off because I think it will lead
to more meaningful connections in my
life.
>> Probably nets out better right in the
long term.
>> I think so. I have this photo here of a
very smaller and
>> so funny. I look at this and I see my
daughter.
>> Really?
>> That was like the first thing when I saw
that photo.
>> At what age did you realize that life
for you was slightly different from the
average person? Like when does a child
realize that?
>> H
I think there was always a lot of
media attention and scrutiny. You see
it, you experience it very early on. And
I think my parents did a really good job
trying to shelter us from it. And it was
different then without social media. You
know, not everyone I think the
experience our children have where
anywhere they go people have a recording
device in their hands, their iPhone um
and can take pictures of them and you
know it's so um you're so exposed during
um during your formative years and
thankfully I did not have that growing
up but there were times I felt it. I
remember
I wanted to be a dancer, a ballet
dancer. And you know, my mom um was an
incredible skier. She skied on the
national team for then Czechoslovakia,
now Czech Republic. And so she really
believed in the importance of of sport
for cultivating discipline and um so she
really encouraged this. And I was
dancing at Giuliard, the school of
American Ballet here in New York. I was
in the Nutcracker and I remember I was
probably eight and I was, you know, like
some small role in the Nutcracker. I was
a party girl and an angel. Those were
like the entry roles where you like
dance at the party, uh, where the the
man with the Nutcracker arrives and then
you're in that angel scene. And I
remember being so excited and was my
first Nutcracker.
And, um, Michael Jackson had just moved
into Trump Tower and was literally our
neighbor in Trump Tower. And my father
sees him one day, you know, passing in
the lobby. I'm with him. I said, 'You
know, my daughter's in the Nutcracker.
You should come. You should come see a
performance. So, he comes to the
Nutcracker with my father at the height
of his fame to watch me dance. And now
this in retrospect could be like, wow,
what a cool experience. But I was
horrified. I'm like, this is I was so
embarrassed. I thought we had ruined the
Nutcracker. Everyone was dancing with
one glove. people who produced the show
were, you know, hysterical that everyone
was dancing with one glove. I thought it
was all my fault and this was like just
a wild childhood experience. I had
things like that happen that were so far
from normal that it's actually like
comical in retrospect, but I think the
the dayto-day was like really grounded.
My grandmother and uh and grandfather
before he passed on my mother's side
really raised us. My grandmother cooked
every meal we ate for, you know, most of
my childhood.
>> And uh Bubby
>> Bubby Bubby.
>> Yeah. So she taught me um a type of
unconditional love and tenderness and um
I think more than anything she was just
this un that's her. She's um
unbelievably nurturing. I'd come home
from school and, you know, before I'd be
out of the shower, she would have
laundered my clothes and folded them and
put them back on my bed. She was always
feeding me and food for her was very
much like an expression of love. I
remember when I became a teenager and
I'd sleep later and later, she'd wake me
up for lunch, you know, just like, god
forbid I wasn't being fed at all at all
hours. But
>> I can see she means the world to you.
>> She does. She's 98 years old and um you
know her health has suffered and you
know it's it's been a little bit of a
difficult time for her but I I feel so
strongly for for me and my children to
have the experience to be there for her
in just like a small fraction of the way
that she was there for me is such an
extraordinary privilege. and for them to
grow up with her at our table every
single meal um each night and her
telling her stories and stories of my
mother who they sadly didn't get to
know. Um
>> are you okay? I can see
>> No, I'm Yes, I'm great. I I have a lot
of um I have a lot of love for this
woman. So,
This doesn't happen to me often.
>> What is that um mixture of emotions that
you're experiencing?
>> Um
she taught me so much just about love
and we were talking before about
connection. Um,
and uh, you know, it's it's been hard to
see her now as she as she struggles, but
um,
but she's uh, it's a blessing to have
her in our home and living with us and
very special person.
Maybe I'll have a tissue.
Thank you.
It's a real credit to her.
>> Yeah.
>> It's often a testament um to the person
and the value that they've added to your
life and how they were there for you
that you would feel
feel the way you do about her and that's
so like visible in your face. You know,
she must have been quite formative.
>> Oh, for sure. Um for sure.
So, she's been
she's an amazing person.
You said that she she was really taking
care of you
>> and and sort of at the age of 10. Mother
and father, I'm assuming very very busy.
>> Yeah.
>> Explain that to me.
>> You know, my mother was an incredible
trailblazer. Um an amazing example for
me of
strength and resilience and glamour and
um determination and ambition. And she
was a great mother, too.
But she would also say like she couldn't
do it alone and she wasn't pretending
she could. So she surrounded us with
people who loved us. We had um two
amazing nannies. One of them worked for
my mother until the day she died. The
other um is worked for my mother until
the day my mother died um and still
works with us today. She worked as after
we grew up she worked as my mother's
personal assistant. So they were very
much part of our lives and and part of
our extended family and of course my
grandmother who she trusted completely
with us. So so she showed me a lot at a
time when
you know not many women were doing what
my mother was doing um inside the
boardroom and on the construction sites
all the time by the way with 5-in heels
and like perfectly caught hair. So she
made it look incredibly easy, but it was
and continues to be very challenging to
balance work and life like that,
especially at a time where what she was
doing was so singular. So she she really
and my mother served as an unbelievable
role model for me for what is possible.
How to be an amazing mother who is
loving and nurturing and fun and
provides for her children and and also
to be unadashedly
um
and doggedly pursuing one's
goals in in a professional capacity. So
she did that when she was married to my
father. she did that um following their
divorce and um and really was just an
amazing an amazing mentor for me. You're
growing up in a context where your
family are privileged, they have um they
have no notoriety and the both parents
are quite absent by way of them being so
busy and they're also kind of
>> I wouldn't say absent but
>> you know my mother wasn't home cooking
us meals. my grandmother was.
>> Mhm.
>> But my mother was home when we ate them
and then she'd go out again. You know,
her and my father were actively building
their life and pursuing their passions.
And for my mom, much like me today, you
know, one of her creative expressions
came in the form of design and
architecture. She wasn't absent and and
you know, neither was my father. So, he
was filled more typical of that
generation male role where he was less
like present. But there was never a
doubt in my mind that I was his top
priority and that he was available to
me. So I used to call him from the pay
phone at uh at Chapen. It was in a broom
closet and never once did he not pick up
and sometimes his office would be filled
with people of um you know he'd be in
the middle of a deal or a negotiation or
some politician or whatever it was and
he'd always put me on speaker phone and
then start the conversation by telling
everyone how I got great grades and I'd
start to blush. Um but he always picked
up.
>> They weren't absent. Did I what?
>> Miss him?
>> No, because I didn't feel like they I
didn't feel like he was absent. it was
just different like he wasn't attending
all of our sports games but by the way
few parents were um you know four
decades ago there's a lot more sort of
active participation like the way I am
in my kids' life the way my husband is I
I think it is you know a little
different especially um for fathers
today than than 30 years ago
>> if I sat Avana your mother here next to
us at the same age you are now what
would be the the the fundamental
differences in in those individuals
You know, it's funny. I think back now
and um my mother
and I are both incredibly similar and
very different. So, she had like
over-the-top style and glamour, you
know, and I think in some ways it was a
reaction to the austerity and the
control of growing up in a communist
country in in then Czechoslovakia.
Like, nobody was going to tell her what
to do. nobody was going to tell her what
to say. So, she actually would make my
father look pissy and was hysterical. I
mean, I spent much of my childhood being
like, "Oh, mom, please stop." You know,
it was really interesting. Um, I feel
like today
because my mother passed away um
unexpectedly um from a fall a few years
ago,
there were just like I had a lot of
questions and um and I really dug into
her story and her history and
um and really studied her almost in a
way that I wish I had done when she was
living and I could speak to her
directly. And I think I understand her a
because I'm at a level of maturity and
I've have some of the same issues, you
know, having young children. And I think
I understand her though better today
than I did in some ways in in her life.
Like I see her more fully.
>> And what did you understand more about
her that you didn't understand while she
was here after she passed? She wrote a
book in the final years of her life that
talked a lot more about her childhood
and I think not uncommon um for people
who have experienced you know a lot of
hardship sometimes they compartmentalize
and it's like forward only and this
whole part of her life she never talked
about and I think when you're younger
you ask a lot less questions like now I
would tell everyone who's listening like
really ask the questions especially if
people are a bit of a vault and are less
inclined to to look back in the past
because I you know all of her life
experience very much shaped her.
>> This was a beautiful photo that I found
of of you and I.
>> That was in uh in Mara Lago on my uh
childhood bed. Very uh ornate.
Um, yeah, she was really I mean she was
impossibly glamorous.
>> Yeah, I couldn't find a photo where she
didn't like incredible photos.
>> 9 years old, your mother and father
split up, divorced.
>> It was quite well publicized. Um, that
your father had an affair with somebody.
And this is actually where the quote
that I referenced earlier about trust
comes in because
>> quite remarkably reporters were waiting
outside of your school to take photos of
you and ask questions about your your
father's affair. And the quote that I
read in GQ said this is a quote from
you. If I didn't have that lesson, I
don't know that I'd be tough. It taught
me not to trust anybody. You can never
let your guard down. And I never really
have since that time.
So that's probably the 25year-old
version of me
>> as as you know there's a lot of truth in
it and I think certain defense
mechanisms we create for ourselves are
actually healthy
>> because it was healthy for me not to be
trusting before I had honed my own
instincts and had learn to understand
people and read people. So I think there
was nothing wrong with a 25 or
27year-old
with my lived experience answering that
way. But um but I do like
>> I completely understand though like
every part of me completely understands
that reaction to that event at like 9
years old.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean reporters being at your school or
just generally you know how that must
have been as as a kid in school. Well,
there was a level of aggression that
like even today wouldn't exist with the
paparazzi then, like to be shouting
things and like reading um quotes from
from tabloids to me as I'm leaving
school. To put this in context, this
divorce apparently garnered more
headlines than the OJ Simpson trial. So,
that was a lot. The difference is that
once I stepped into my home, it was a
safe place. you know, unless the TVs
were blaring, which obviously they
weren't during that period of time. So,
I think the difference today for parents
and that I think about a lot with my
kids is you just can't protect them in
the same way. Like social media
amplifies everything. So, while that
experience with those reporters was
extremely combative and aggressive and
like totally unacceptable in a way that
I don't think society would allow today,
today it's very much more in children's
faces. you know, they can acquire the
information they need. And obviously,
when you're young, you're curious.
>> Again, I'm trying to like world build in
my head because I think understanding
that early context helps us understand
everybody. And if that was my early
context, I think you'd be you'd see the
fingerprints on me today,
>> you know?
>> Well, I think we're all, you know, I
think about it with my own children.
like I
I grew up with a lot of privilege and um
and I've lived an extraordinary life and
you know I never worried where my next
meal came from. I never worried about
being able to pay for the best school
that I was able to get into. And so by
so many metrics my life was extremely
comfortable and easy. And I do think
back like some of the challenges the the
moments that were disgusting or
uncomfortable or you know even just the
fact of um my parents' marriage being to
torn apart.
I think those create the pressure that
turns you into who you become.
>> Did you know what it meant at 9 years
old? Cuz I again I transport myself
back.
>> I probably then you couldn't look things
up as easily. Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Newspaper,
>> you know, I I don't know what I thought.
I I think I was probably more scared
than anything of like the mob and the
lights and um the surprise of it all. Um
>> do you know what them separating me?
Like did they have a conversation with
you and say, you know, we're we're
splitting up or was it
>> They did. And I think the experience I
had, albeit
it was televised. Um, but it was very
much like any other child who's dying
whose parents are separating. You start
to wonder,
you know, will I be loved? Will I be
forgotten? What does this mean? Um, you
want them to get back together. You're
hoping. You're trying to create peace
between them. Um, rekindle the love. All
the things that I think are like deeply
normal and and human. And you found out
about the divorce by seeing a newspaper
on your way to school one day.
>> Um, yes.
That wasn't the plan. Um, they used to
have uh the big news boxes with the
newspaper. So,
>> what did it say?
>> My parents had sat me down that
afternoon. That's when they had intended
to, but it had it had come out in the
morning.
>> What did the newspaper say?
>> I don't remember. I remember the photo.
There was a picture of them with a rip
down the middle. It was not an easy
situation for a child. But um that
experience I always look for like what
is the positive in any situation and you
know the positive for me and my siblings
were we really like bonded in a
different type of way because we were
going through it together.
>> It must be so interesting being in your
shoes because you look me and you're
both aware that people they want to
drive a a wedge between you and your
father. They want a headline. They want
you to say something. I can see it
within you that you have a real desire
to be like open and transparent, but if
I was in your shoes, I'd be thinking
like everyone's trying to trip me out.
Everyone's trying to make a headline um
on on me and my life. They want to drive
a wedge between me and my father. It's
difficult. It must be difficult. Like
even I think about it as a podcast. The
podcast, you know, the podcast gets big.
I say the wrong line,
>> you know. You know, I think one of the
things I've learned under moments in my
life of tremendous sort of pressure and
scrutiny is um to like find the signal
in the noise. And that's probably the
thing that has been most helpful to me.
It can become quite turbulent. I find
myself sometimes literally like dancing
in the eye of the hurricane. It's been
many years of my life, but there's a lot
of like peace within me. So I just don't
get distracted by by the outside noise
and um and I think if you know what you
stand for then it really is just noise.
>> When did you have to learn this? Because
am I right in thinking you this is the
first time that I saw the Trump family
during the apprentice. So obviously you
know growing up as a kid big fan of
business we had the UK apprentice but
the US one was much more interesting in
my in my opinion.
>> So this is when I first understand who
your father is and who you are. What was
the sentiment around you as a family at
this point? Because again, people can't
remember
>> pre vortex.
>> It was the biggest show in the world at
one point. Um, it was this massive
phenomenon. you know, he had been very
famous in sort of New York and in real
estate and in business circles, but this
kind of like expanded awareness of him
beyond those New York circles onto
um a global stage. So, there was a lot
of attention and a lot of excitement.
You know, he was very similar to how he
is now. He said exactly what he was
thinking, which could be polarizing at
times, but it's part of what people
loved about him. I think the thing about
my father and my mother is they're like
deeply authentic. So you can disagree,
but there's a certain amount of like
respect for the cander of it. Um, and
the lack of fear to say what you're
thinking because so many people are sort
of afraid to be them true, their true
selves.
>> You're more delicate with your words.
>> Yeah, but I know exactly who I am.
That's why the noise doesn't affect me.
I'm really proud of the fact that, you
know, I've lived through some incredibly
intense times where people are taking
cheap shots and swinging and I don't
punch back because I don't
believe in
sort of spending my time and focus like
being combative like jumping into that
particular arena and like the nasty
swirl of social media. It's just it's
not for me and I've been consistent in
that my whole life and I feel like that
sets an amazing example to my children.
>> Where did you learn that? What is it
that you've read? What are the sort of
>> you just have to be yourself and you
have to be true to yourself and like I
don't allow that noise to distract me.
We were talking um earlier about
stoicism. I think like Marcus Aurelius's
meditations is so informative on so many
levels. I mean here you have somebody
who was literally an emperor and he's
writing this journal in a tent in a
battlefield. So his perspective is
amazing and he once wrote that the soul
becomes dyed the color of its thoughts
and I think about that all the time. The
cost to me of living in a way that's
inconsistent and not aligned with what
feels right, what models the right thing
for my children, what feels inherently
true to me. It's too expensive. it's too
expensive for for my soul, so I won't do
it. So, you know, there there have been
times when the incoming and I say, well,
but that isn't right or this isn't right
or I want to correct it. And then I say
like, what's the cost of doing it? Theo
has another great quote. It's something
paraphrasing to the effect of, you know,
the cost of anything is the amount of
your life you're willing to exchange for
it. I focus on those things that like
elevate my soul, um my my joy, my
happiness, my connection to the people I
love and care about.
>> Have you always been there? Because you
seem more stoic now, but you know,
>> I have like I'm much more naturally like
this. Like I feel things like a lot of
things.
>> You're a bit of an empath, right?
>> Oh, for sure.
>> Okay. Yeah, that makes sense.
>> Uh so I have not always been like this.
It's like I had to work to be like this
and I had to I think mature and I had to
gain like confidence and it took me a
while to really let people in. And I
think it was after my children were born
that I really experienced a different
type of love. It like cracks you open
and you're never the same, you know, and
and you want more of that feeling. Like
I I'm very intentional about everything
that I do. even sitting here today like
I I have zero interest in spending two
hours having a conversation with
somebody I think is like a bully um
because they get good podcast you know
like I I like having conversations with
people I think are interesting and
curious but in business as well like I'm
I'm you know I do less things and I do
them with a lot more focus and
intention. You've lived an extraordinary
life and it's a very anomalous one. But
actually the lesson there about being
intentional
in every sense of the word, not just
with what you do every day, but also
what you let occupy your mind is one
that I think everybody listening
>> might derive a lot of value from because
we live everybody lives on a spectrum of
the world clawing at them
>> to deviate from who they are. um some
you know one end of the spectrum if I
take myself back to when I was I don't
know 16 years old the world you know
other than my mother telling me she
wanted me to go be doctor lawyer
whatever the world wasn't really pulling
me away from myself but then on the
other end of the spectrum you know I'm
33 now you know every time I have a
podcast guest on someone's mad at me
>> and everything I say can be spun in
whatever so you also on this side of the
spectrum you have to get really really
clear as you said on like who you are
and what matters
>> well I think that's key like if if you
don't know who you are the mob wins.
>> Oh, 100%.
>> Because they tell you who you are and
then you start to believe it.
>> Once you know who you are,
>> you feel sorry for the people who are
like screaming at each other on on
social media. It takes like a beat to
get there. Like I think it it takes a
lot of work to to really understand
yourself. And I think sometimes
modern society it praises sort of speed
and fast pace and um you know
accessibility and being available and
responding quickly then people wonder
like why don't they know themselves like
why aren't they connected to something
bigger and they're not taking the time.
I take time to shut down and like really
go inward and ask myself every time I
have a big decision like what feels
right and even if it's hard to make a
decision like whether it's a no or a yes
if it feels aligned with your values and
who you are like it never is a mistake
ever.
>> You grew up in the uh you know with a
with a family and a father that are very
prominent. at some point do you have to
make the decision to become your own
person like because I was wondering if
in that context you there's a there's a
pressure to kind of like be the same
person in every regard
>> to believe all the same things to live
the same life to go the same path
>> is there some point in your journey
where you where you go do you know what
I've actually got to like figure out I
can see a little smirk in the corner of
your mouth
>> well no I think about it with my own
children because as a parent it's very
easy to see them as
you know a lot of parents they they view
their children as extens ions of
themselves and I really try not to do
that. Like they are their own people
just like I'm my own person sometimes in
the context of a broader public
narrative.
Everything's sort of comingled and
related. But we're all our own people.
We obviously have conditioning. We have
learned behaviors. We have um some of
which are great. Some of which we spend
part of our adulthood um unwinding.
But we're all like fundamentally unique
and special. And I work really hard to
make sure my kids see themselves, each
of them individually, that they know how
much I love them as like perfect,
complete human beings, not I love you
because of this accomplishment or
because of this sort of external
validation that you've received because
you're sort of perfect as as you are and
like in your essence. So, so my parents
taught me a lot a lot. I love them so
much. I'm like them in some ways. I'm
very dissimilar to them in other ways.
But even though I was like the
peacemaker in our house, I was also like
very like true to myself. And they
created and I give them credit for this,
they created an environment where like
disscent was okay. And so I could agree
or disagree and share it with each of
them and um do so respectfully and and
privately. and that was our home.
>> Um, you started off in real estate. You
you worked in a It sounded like to me
you were basically an intern at a a a
different real estate company before
moving into the the family business and
in the family business, you know,
heavily male-dominated space. I heard
you talk about how actually being a
woman in that context proved to be in
your mind an advantage of sorts. What is
the the context there? And I'm in 2026
right now, so I don't have the
perspective of what it was like to be a
young woman in the real estate industry,
presuming in New York. Yeah.
>> Some sort of 20 years ago.
>> Well, I think I was like underestimated
twice. First, being the child of
accomplished parents. There was an
expectation that I on one hand some
people thought I was like a savant
because I was their child but most
people
thought they would be um that I would
phone it in that I would lack sort of
the thought process, the ambition, the
preparedness. So, I I always worked like
twice as hard as everyone else to sort
of prove my worth and prove um my
ability to to be in these rooms where
truthfully often times I was in them
before I was prepared to be in them. So,
that was, you know, on my mind. But I
think being underestimated is is not a
bad thing. I think it's like a very
powerful thing actually. And it almost
always worked to the detriment of the
person who underestimated me. So, I
think if you're somebody who's prepared
and somebody underestimates you, well,
guess what? They're not. So, when you're
dealing with people who are extremely
accomplished, like do the work. Like,
know what you're doing because probably
they haven't done the work when they
know they're dealing with you. And I
think as a young woman in real estate
especially, you know, there were there
were women in sales and there were women
in marketing, but there were very few
women in development and construction
and finance and acquisitions.
And
I think um I harnessed both the belief
some of it may be stemming from my own
insecurity but the belief that the
people would underestimate me. I
harnessed that like sort of fear, that
sentiment and I used it to sort of
propel me and I used it to give me
motivation and and drive and then I also
would use it against the people who
underestimated me just because I I was
always prepared. I was overprepared. I I
always did the work. I heard you
described as um from people that worked
with you at the time a naturalb born
deal maker. And this kind of overlays
with what you're saying there that if
someone underestimates you, they're
actually setting themselves up to be
surprised or
>> Well, I'd prefer to be underestimated
than overestimated any day of the week.
>> Give me specifics on what what
environment that creates for you to then
win in a deal. I think in in negotiation
it's like incredibly important to
know what the other person wants.
Sometimes you can learn that through
research. Very infrequently though, like
you have to listen. Like you're probably
a great negotiator because you're an
incredible listener. Silence can also be
a weapon. People get very uncomfortable
in moments of silence and then they
start talking. And I think the more you
can get a person to share with you
what they consider to be a win, the more
you can potentially accomplish something
where you give
where you really have like a mutual
win-win. Like I've seen negotiations
where you give up very little, but the
person feels incredibly happy because
it's what they wanted.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Now, when you're dealing with
like a negotiation that's purely price,
that's kind of different. That's like a
very simple transaction. It's, you know,
but very few negotiations are purely
that, you know, one of first and
foremost in a negotiation like like make
sure you understand what the other
person wants because you may be able to
give it to them at at very little cost
and then everyone's happy. And I also
think there's a lot of value in like
authentically building relationships.
though, you know, some of the the best
deals I ever did were uh derivatives of
really like getting to know someone like
authentically and genuinely. And um they
want you to win, you want them to win.
And those are are like really beautiful
types of transactions. And you know, I
believe in you know, a lot of the
projects I'm working on now are about
like creating things. Like I like
building tangible things. I like
creating things that um that uplift. to
like solving challenging problems and um
and you don't do that alone. You do that
through partnership. You do that through
coalitions of people who share your
passion and interest and um and that's
very rewarding.
>> When you hire people, what are you
looking for for your businesses? Are
there I mean, everyone's got their own
hiring bias and it often stems from
their past experiences who's burnt them
in the past. when you're looking to hire
someone for one of your organizations or
for some of the projects we'll talk
about in a second, what what are the
like the key characteristics?
>> I think first and foremost, you want
someone with a strong sense of self and
a strong like orientation towards like
agency, like somebody who has agency.
It's very hard to teach people, you
know, you could have a brilliant person,
but if they don't have like good
judgment or if they're not like a
self-starter, it's very hard to give
them that. It's very hard to sort of
give them good judgment. And some of
it's like street smarts, right? We
talked before about, you know, how can
you both be trustworthy
and not be disappointed or burn too
often? You have an instinct about a
person
>> and you can read a room and and that's
like EQ skills and those are those are a
little bit harder to teach. So, I look
for that.
>> I look for good people at the end of the
day. like I don't want to do a deal with
I don't want to work with people I don't
enjoy that I don't think are like good
people um because I don't want to spend
my time with somebody who I don't trust
or who I don't respect. So that's like
really core and fundamental for me. you
know, for somebody who's working with
me, I actually tell my kids this all the
time because I think so much of the
outside world is like, "Impress me by
what you do." Like, "Impress me by what
you accomplish. The grades, the
trophies, the the badges of like
external validation and success." Like,
our whole life is oriented towards that,
the validation that comes from the
outside world. So like I always want my
kids to know like how I'm going to
validate them is like be a good person.
Like you want to impress me like be a
good person.
>> Was that the case for you? Cuz when I
look at
>> Probably not.
>> I look at the Trump family for me as an
outsider looked like a competition
between siblings and even when I think
about your father
>> I think because we're so competitive and
hard. Yeah. No, I think um I think it
all like worked out and we're all I I
like to think you know my my siblings
and I grew up with um like good values
and uh but no like we were in a more
like I was like very competitive with my
siblings like you know my mom was like a
disciplinarian there was like a high
expectation of like performance and
success um
>> and when you're in that when you're
calling collect your father he's
reciting your great grades to the room
of people He's in. No, no, no. That was
>> That mattered. And And it matters to a
lot of parents. And by the way, it's not
bad like having an incredibly high
standard. And to some degree,
>> Yeah. And I think look, I I think it's
>> a lot of parents like I think especially
like my mom was an immigrant to this
country, there's like a high standard.
Um and uh and she didn't like humor
fools, right? One of the things I'm most
proud of, I look at my daughter and
there's no bar I could set for her that
the bar she sets for herself isn't
higher. So like I actually view my job
as a parent with her is to like give her
permission to not like strive for
perfection.
>> You go on to build a business in the
jewelry industry and fashion industry.
Um there was I was reading about there
was a point in your career where you
were you were offered a job by Anna
Wintor. Yeah.
>> At Vogue. And your I think your father
did kind of want you to go in that
direction, but you wanted to go in the
real estate business direction.
>> She called me actually on the day I
graduated from university. I went to
Warden School of Business at University
of Pennsylvania and she offered me a job
at Vogue and I was like incredibly
honored and flattered and groggy because
she called me at 8:00 in the morning
which calling a college student at 8:00
in the morning, you might as well call
them at 4:30 in the morning, you know?
like that was that I was like deeply
aware from when I was a young girl that
like I wanted to go into real estate.
Life has taken me in different
directions and and interestingly now I'm
returning with some amazing projects
back to my real estate roots. But I love
architecture. I love design. I love it
as an expression of self. If you look at
a city skyline and it's an expression of
like a vision for
um of hope and optimism and the amount
of courage that took to build each of
those buildings and it's it's
extraordinary.
>> But you did go into the fine jewelry at
26 years old and then at 33 you launched
Ivanka Trump.com and you were in a huge
amount of major retailers including
Nordstrom, Neiman Marcus and that's
really also that's what I knew you first
for. I knew you for running a fashion
business which was doing exceptionally
well. I think from what I read it was
making hundreds of millions of dollars
and then you shut it down.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It was kind of like
lightning in a a bottle. I caught a
moment. So, I was um still sort of
leading the charge at our family real
estate business. I had young children at
home um or was just starting to have uh
children when when I first launched Fine
Jewelry. Ultimately, we ended up having
11 different categories, apparel,
footwear, sunglasses, fragrance. Um,
but we created an accessibly priced line
that was feminine and beautiful, but for
like a multi-dimensional woman. Like, at
the time when I was coming up, the
outfits that women were buying for work
were so far from aspirational and they
couldn't transition with the woman to
the date night. they would have that
evening or after work drinks with their
girlfriends. It was like nobody was
posting on Instagram like what they were
wearing to work. And so we thought like
let's bridge the gap and create
something for a modern woman. And it
caught fire. And it was
>> how big an amazing success. We were
doing um close to $800 million in sales
annually um when I shut it down when I
went into government. It was great. But
>> you were doing 800 million in sales
annually when you shut it down.
>> Yeah.
>> Why did you shut it down?
>> I went into government and you always
have to sort of be moving forward and I
had built a team of women who were
oriented towards forward momentum and I
had to put it on ice and this was all
just part of the rules of complying with
the office of government and ethics. So
they basically look at everything you
have and they say sell this, put this
into a trust, do this, do that, do this.
So you do that and and for my own
business, they weren't allowed to use my
image. They weren't allowed to grow the
business in terms of new accounts or
internationally. And that was fine for a
moment, but at the end of the day, you
need like growth. And so I thought it
would be easier to end on a high note
than to um allow the business to sort of
stagnate. And I also felt like for
myself, I'm always looking forward like
I don't like to look back. And I feel
the
experience of of this new experience, I
mean, serving was so expanding.
>> Most people wouldn't give up an $800
million annual business to go into
government.
>> Why did you,
>> you know, I I
>> It's your baby as well. You know, it's
like
>> Yeah. I, you know, I thought about the
version of me in 40 years that when
asked the question to serve by my
father, who at the time knew no one in
in Washington DC at all, said no and
just proceeded with life as usual. And
that didn't like sit right with me. So,
I had no intention of serving. And a few
weeks after he won, he asked Jared and
me to go with him and sort of help him
navigate this new environment. And my
eyes grew big. And he joked with me.
He's like, "But I have to warn you,
they're going to come at you hard.
They're probably going to hate you.
You're too young. You're too." And he
like, I'm like, "Oh my god." I'm like,
"What?" That was like the anti- sale.
But, you know, he asked us for help. Um,
and I feel incredibly
privileged that he gave us the
opportunity to serve a country we love
so much. We hadn't been expecting it. We
hadn't set up our lives for it. We were
loving the path we were on and and the
work we were doing. But you also, you
know, can't put your head in the sand
and like life had changed. As much as
I'd like to say like, oh, he wins
business as usual, there is no business
as usual. Your life has changed.
>> You didn't choose this though. In fact,
you didn't choose most of these things.
I look at your life and I go that from a
very young age you've not chosen the
context which you've been thrust into
because of your your father's ambitions
and I mean I can see it in your face
that it kind of rings true
>> but I think that's true for all of us
right to some degree like our path is
determined by our circumstance I
>> not really not really in the same way
>> this is a little bit different with
politics and the presidency but
>> but even from 9 years old you know
you're not choosing to leave school and
have reporters uh treat you like that
and you're not choosing these other
things along the way and then your
father decides he wants to be president
of the United States. It's not like he
had a political career where he like
built up slowly. It's like he woke up
one day and was like
>> was drinking water from a fire hose for
all of us. It was a lot. Normally you
cut your teeth on, you know, some local
election as a family have the
experience.
The first time he ever run for office
was president and he won. So, it was a
radical adjustment period for um for all
of us. But
>> did you think you would
>> Boy did it. Oh, yeah. I did.
>> I mean, it was it was hard to believe
myself because everyone was saying that
he wouldn't. And I'd say, "Well, these
people probably know what they're
talking about, but it felt like he
would." And, you know, so for me, that
time was extraordinary because I really
believed, you know, I lived in New York
City. I thought I was around surrounded
by diverse minds and opinions and
perspectives and viewpoints and I really
thought I had sort of a lot of exposure
to ideas and
his campaign like ripped it open for me
and that I realized like the bubble that
I was in and suddenly I got out into the
country and I heard from people who had
very divergent views on a number of
issues. Some of it reinforced my
existing beliefs. Other times it
completely changed my perspective and
and orientation. So it was extremely
mindexpanding. So when you ask like,
"Oh, why didn't I go back to what I was
doing?" I think like, you know, you you
get thrown into something and you learn
and you grow and you change. And um and
I felt as challenging it was as that
moment in my life to um to say yes when
when my father asked us to to go help
him. I felt like it was an amazing
privilege to be able to serve. So new
year always has a strange energy to it
because people start talking about their
goals, fresh starts and new habits. But
the reality is that most people carry
the same ideas they had last year into
the new year. I'm guilty of that too.
and they still don't end up doing
anything with them. And I get why
starting something new, especially if
it's a business or a project, is
overwhelming. Before you start, you're
looking for the perfect moment and to be
the perfect version of yourself when
really what matters most is taking that
first step. If you've had an idea for a
while, a product, a store, something
you've been sitting on, our sponsor,
Shopify, makes it easy to get started
because you can build your store, sell
on socials, take payments, use AI tools,
and manage everything all in one place.
So, if 2026 is the year you finally back
yourself, go to shopify.co.uk/bartlet
and start selling. And you can sign up
for a $1 per month trial right now, too.
Just go to shopify.co.uk/bartlet.
I promise you, you don't need to have it
all figured out. You just need to start.
I run multiple companies that have
multiple sales teams. And one of the
things as a founder of a company that's
often confusing is you find it hard to
figure out where sales are. So about 10
years ago, I started using Pipe Drive in
my former company and it's also the
reason why I switched over all of my
commercial teams in my current media
company called Steven.com to use Pipe
Drive as well. Not only do they sponsor
this show, but they've been an
incredibly effective way of scaling our
sales engine over the years. Pipe Drive
is an easy to use intelligent CRM. And
at its very core, it makes your sales
process visible through one dashboard. a
visual pipeline showing every deal, what
stage it's in, what needs to happen
next, and it's all in real time with no
delay. It doesn't magically close the
deal for you, of course, but it does
replace complexity with clarity. If you
want to join over a 100,000 companies
already using Piperive, you can use my
link for a 30-day free trial with no
credit card payment needed. Head to
piperive.com/ceeo
to get started. That's
piperive.com/ceeo.
I'll see you over there. I watched
interviews going back to the 1980s where
it sounded like your father was playing
with the idea. I remember that Oprah
interview that's subsequently gone viral
of him saying that um if it got so bad
in the US he would never rule it out
totally. He thought he would win because
he's never gone into anything to lose as
I think you said and even 1980 in an
interview with Rona Beret can't
pronounce that name he said maybe I'd
run for president I don't know. Did you
have any sense that this was at all on
the horizon in
>> Not really.
>> That's interesting.
>> No, it was, you know, it was actually
where we discussed things that weren't
sort of the normal how was your day at
school. It was we spoke a lot about real
estate and about
um and about building and we were going
to go into the family business and and I
do think he sort of toyed with it in his
mind um for a while. I I do remember
once thinking it was real. I was 16 and
I was at boarding school and I called
him up. I go, "Oh my god, I read that
you're going to run for president. This
is going to ruin my life."
I think I was like hysterical and he's
like, "Don't worry about it. Not
happening." You know, I think he was he
was thinking about the options he was
given as a voter and he was dissatisfied
and I think he was beginning to
formulate his perspective on what he
would do differently. But it was not my
childhood that was not an ambition of
his that was at least articulated to to
us. You know some of the ideas you
mentioned that Oprah interview he was
talking about
um trade policy being deeply unfair to
American workers. you know, his
viewpoint remained consistent over time
and remains consistent to this day on
exactly that about trade policy and and
many of many of the things he
articulated then are very true for him
to this day.
>> And then in 2015 when you're 33, my age,
you learn two weeks before he announces
that he's going to announce that he
wants to run for president
>> again. How do you receive that? is in
like an existential panic like you have
>> we came together as a family in
Bedminster. Um and he shared with us his
intention and he asked me to introduce
him and I said to him I'm like well are
you really doing this
um are you really going to do this? He
was coming down the escalator and I'm
trying to like introduce him and give
this speech. I'm like, is he going to
get up here and actually? It was so
quick. But I think, you know, I think he
had debated it in his mind for a long
time and then when he pulled the
trigger, it was
full steam.
>> Life hasn't been the same since in many
respects.
>> Mm- No, it hasn't. But it's been I mean,
it's been an extraordinary ride. There
have been highs and there have been
lows, but um we've done a lot of living.
So,
>> a lot of living.
>> A lot of living.
>> Of which you spent four years working in
the White House.
>> Mhm. Some of your sort of key headline
achievements are doubling the child tax
credit from $1,000 to $2,000, benefiting
40 million Americans with an average of
$2.2,000 $2,000 per year, helping secure
paid family leave for federal workers,
helping pass the Great American Outdoors
Act, which is one of the largest
Conservative bills since the National
Park System was created, leading efforts
to modernize career and technical
education, providing 1.3 billion
annually to over 13 million students,
and helping to pass nine pieces of
legislation combating human trafficking
and child exploitation.
And then it ended.
>> Were you happy it ended? cuz I saw it
with Michelle Obama. She seemed happy.
>> I left it all on the field, you know? I
I don't look back and say
like I I I don't have regrets. Like I
worked as hard as I could and I'm
incredibly
proud of what I was able to accomplish
in in those four years. and um like I
don't regret it in any way, but it's you
know it's a sacrifice um to my children
and it's um and it's it's it's hard work
you know so I feel both incredibly
privileged for the opportunity but also
I don't have what they refer to as PTOIC
fever you know there's some people that
once they have the experience of of
being in those rooms and and close to
that type of power they just like hang
around the hoop constantly like cycling
back in. I feel like I wasn't expecting
to serve in this capacity, at least not
at this stage of my life. My father
asked me to help him. We uprooted our
lives and went and did just that and
scored a lot of wins. I mean, you think
about something like the child tax
credit. 40 million American families
benefited from that policy. An average
of $2,400 in their pockets.
That's extraordinarily meaningful and
consequential and I'm so proud to have
been able to do that. nine pieces of
human trafficking legislation, the work
that I did around vocational education
and skills training, which is all the
more relevant as we sort of surf the
oncoming tsunami that is AI. you know,
the fact that we were able to um get the
private sector to commit to skilling or
res-killing 16 million American workers,
the fact that we were able to facilitate
the creation of a million apprenticeship
opportunities in in the United States,
like these are are deeply meaningful.
So, I
I'm so proud of my service. I I feel
deeply honored that
he trusted me to pursue these different
verticals and and to work alongside of
him. And I also know that it's really
hard and for my children, you know, my
first responsibility is to be their mom.
It was true then as well, of course. And
and I did the best I could every single
day to be everywhere I needed to be. But
my kids are a different age now and
there's a finite period of time before
they leave our home. I think, you know,
I look at at my teenage daughter, she's
14 and even if like a quarter of my
interactions with her through her closed
bedroom door, like I need to be present
and I need to be there. It's not
theoretical for me because now I know
the sacrifice
that they would have to bear the cost to
them of if I went back into service and
I'm not willing to let them pay that
price. So for me it's like actually a
rather easy decision. I made it
immediately. You know that in this
moment I'm where I need to be. It's also
a different time. You know, now my
father has a deep bench of people
raising their hand who want to help and
participate. That wasn't true before.
He's really refined his policies, his
beliefs, and has a lot of conviction in
terms of what he wants to do. So, so I
feel like for him, it's amazing. He's
got the team he needs and um and for me,
I think, you know, my priorities are are
my family, and that just feels really
good and right for me.
>> What weren't you prepared for? I asked
the same question to Michelle when she
was here about, you know, you get that
phone call from your dad and he says,
"Come, come help. One has a vision of
what that might look like, but there's
surprises." Michelle talked to me about
so many of the things she had no idea
would be the case.
>> I wasn't prepared for you're not
prepared for any of it. There's nothing
that trains you for the experience. And
I think one of the things you realize
pretty quickly is like power, just like
money, makes people more of what they
already are. And you see that very much
in playing out in in politics and and in
life, right? I also think you realize
people are just people. Like you look at
and I'm you know I had exposure to some
of the great leaders of business and now
I was being exposed to um to leaders on
a global stage of countries. Um,
sometimes they were monarchies, other
times they were elected democracies and
then all sorts of varants of of that,
you know, were and and you realize at
the end of the day like people are
people, you know, some of them their
their kids don't speak to them. They got
in a fight with their wife that morning.
They're, you know, they're just people.
And now some of them feel
extraordinarily historic. You meet a
person and say, "This person feels
consequential." others of them you leave
and say, "I wonder how this person ever
got elected to to this, you know, high
office." But, um, but I think it it
removes the veil and and the mystery and
I think it removed for me a lot of any
of like intimidation I may have in like
interacting with another human being.
>> Your security situation must have
changed quite considerably. So,
>> it did. Yeah.
>> You know, and because politics is a
dangerous game. I think I I heard
something that said being president is
the most dangerous job in the world when
you look at the fatality rate and
obviously we've seen political
assassinations in this country even in
recent times but your father was also
shot at hit in the ear when he was on
the campaign trail more recently.
What's that been like and what does it
actually can you give me any specifics
on what that actually like means when
you become involved in politics? How
does life change from a security
perspective?
Yeah,
I think
well it changes radically. Now we're
protected by US Secret Service and I'm
so grateful to to the men and women who
who take care of my family um took care
of my father, protected him and uh
risking their own lives to do so and now
do so for for me and and my children. So
very grateful uh to all of them. But
it's it's it's scary. We live in um very
troubling times and like you know the
fact that there is a correlation between
service and violence is um
is uh terrible in and of itself. But but
that's the the world we live in. So, you
know, I have to acknowledge that reality
and defend my family as as best I can
and make sure they're protected. And I'm
very fortunate. The the Secret Service
are the best in the world at doing that.
Where were you in 2024 in July when you
when you heard the news that your father
had been shot in the ear? There was an
assassination attempt on his life. Do
you remember where you were? Like what's
that like as as a daughter? What are all
the feelings and thoughts?
>> I was in Bedminster, New Jersey, and um
there was a lot of commotion and um the
televisions were on so I saw it almost
immediately. Not in my house. I actually
don't love watching television.
Um but out by the pool in the beastro
and um it was almost real time. It was
before he had stood back up
that I had seen um what was transpiring
and um two of my children were there. Um
so you know my first reaction was to
turn them away. Um,
but
it was incredibly difficult.
Interestingly, I knew real time in that
moment that he was fine. Like, I had I
just knew that
like it wasn't his time. So, I was
horrified and I was scared and I was
protective of my children, but I also
I didn't believe like the worst possible
outcome had transpired. Thank God. And
um and thank God it it hadn't.
And then I saw him that night when he
came home from the hospital because he
was also staying. That morning he had
left from Bedminster. And that evening
he he returned after he left the
hospital and um it's late 1 2:00 in the
morning and Jared and I stayed up and we
met his his car as he was pulling in and
um I just feel
feel like just incredibly lucky that he
was protected on that day. But it's, you
know, when
you can't take things for granted in
life, and I've learned that in numerous
ways, that being one of them. Um, when
my mom passed prematurely,
when my husband had a scare with cancer,
you know, all of these challenges that
remind you how finite and how precious
every moment of this life we live are.
make you realize you just can't take
anything for granted. And I think as you
move through them and you know, God
willing, you're able to. And we were so
fortunate that day that
that this was a failed attempt to take
his life. Um, not a realized one. But
you just I think you you recommmit
to sort of love and connection and to
a recognition of um how short our time
here on earth is and how you have to
value it.
>> Someone shooting at your dad um and
trying to kill your dad. This is quite a
difficult question to ask, but it's like
if if um most of us will never be able
to relate to the fact that
members of the public want our parents
to be deceased and that's the reality of
the the situation for your father is
someone shot at him was trying to
execute him publicly. And um I wonder
how that again doesn't make you negative
to the world
>> because I don't allow it to.
What does that accomplish being negative
towards the world? I think that brings
more negativity into the world. Even for
the person that shot at your father,
>> there's a lot of sickness there. And
I,
you know, I think that
forgiveness is a difficult thing in in
this regard, but I think you have to
um
his living
was a blessing.
So I could look at what happened and be
rightfully traumatized by the experience
and nobody could really argue with that.
But
you have to you have to move through it.
And and on the opposite side of that is
the fact that he's with us today, that
he didn't die, that my father is alive.
And that is an extraordinary blessing
for me as his as his daughter. In life,
you have a choice only in how you
respond. And I choose to
see the positive outcome that
that transpired and dwell there.
>> The mind plays out scenarios, right? The
mind plays out the scenario that where
he he didn't make it, where the he
turned his head in the other direction,
the bullet hit him
>> and you presumably played out that
scenario of what how different life
would have been. Well, seeing it on
repeat for months on television on the
news was certainly like not the easiest
thing and you know that's part of why I
just even before I didn't I never loved
watching the news. I'll read the news
but but no I mean he's here you know
really felt like um a miracle and a
blessing and and that's what I focus on.
I can see the emotion again in you which
is again it's fascinating to me because
I've you know I've heard you know people
around you speak about it but the the
emotional toll seems to be more still
sort of present in you about that
incident than it does about other people
that I've heard speak about this
>> well he's my father he's my father and
he almost lost his life that day but he
didn't and I feel truly grateful for
that
>> and in this second season of his
presidential career you decide that you
want to pursue um many other things,
many other things, many other business
developments and um real estate
developments. You step away from
politics in 2022, I believe. You
announced that you would not be
returning for the third election
campaign. Uh you said, "This time
around, I'm choosing to prioritize my
young children and the private life
we're creating as a family. I do not
plan to be involved in politics." You
also said on Lex Lex's podcast,
"Politics is a pretty dark world.
There's a lot of darkness, a lot of
negativity, and it's just really at odds
with what feels good to me as a human
being. I was thinking this earlier on
about 30 minutes ago. I was thinking,
your nature, as I've known you, seems to
be the antithesis of this type of world,
like fame.
>> Totally true. You know,
>> there's this like gladatorial aspect of
it that's just like not for me. I care
deeply about policy, about helping
people, and I think there's all sorts of
ways to do that. and and and I'm doing
that now in in the private sector, but I
don't like politics, but I I do care
about policy um quite deeply and I've
tried to focus on on that element of
service.
>> And do you feel the need to express you
never do because you don't punch back at
the world publicly, which is I think
something to be admired. And I I've
learned actually quite a lot from
everything you said there about not
feeling the need to like punch back at
the world.
>> It takes training.
>> It like takes real training. I was
actually reading uh recently uh
about the crow and I thought it was like
a great metaphor for life. So crow is
like a highly intelligent animal,
extraordinarily so in some cases, but it
can get aggressive and territorial and
it's one of the only animals that will
actually attack an eagle. Like a crow
will go and just sometimes because it's
being territorial and other times for
fun. And the crow will actually like mob
the eagle and it will land on its back
and it will start pecking it. And the
eagle's response to this, which
naturally the eagle's
many times over larger than the crow,
isn't to like twist and turn and knock
the crow off or um defend itself and and
and then go on the offense. It's just to
fly up. And it flies up while the crow
continues to like just peck at its at
its back. It flies up and up. And the
crow is not built for high altitude
flight. So at a certain point as the
eagle flies up, not expending any energy
in the counterattack, the crow just
falls off.
>> It can't sustain the altitude.
So I and I kind of love that analogy for
life because you have a choice. You
know, you can turn around, you can fight
back, probably the eagle would win or
you can just, you know, play the game on
your own terms. And I I think about that
sometimes and I thought it was like a
brilliant metaphor for dealing with the
noise.
>> And you trained that muscle
>> for sure.
>> So there was a time when you did care.
>> For sure. Because I there was a time
when I was just like confused. I'm like
well but I didn't even do that. Like
what are you talking about? Like I don't
even know what you're and and then
there's a sense of well that's unfair.
Like that's an unfair attack. And then
you realize like a lot of it's unfair
especially in politics. It's like it's
just like a team sport and people attack
and you know and and people also, you
know, put you up on a pedestal and you
just can't get distracted by either. You
just have to be yourself and uh you have
to fly up, let the crows fall off and um
and that's it. That's all you can do.
>> Do any of you remember a conversation I
had on this podcast with anthropologist
Dr. Daniel Lieberman? It was one of the
most viewed conversations of all time on
the Diary of a CEO. And interestingly,
the most replayed moment of that entire
conversation was when I talked about a
specific pair of shoes that I wear.
They're called Barefoot Shoes, and
they're made by a brand called Vivo
Barefoot, who have become one of the
sponsors of this show. Now, all of their
shoes have significantly reduced
support, which gives my feet the
opportunity to strengthen just by
wearing them. And research from
Liverpool University backs this up.
They've shown that wearing Vivo Barefoot
shoes for 6 months can increase foot
strength by up to 60%. So if you want to
start strengthening your feet, which are
the foundation for the rest of your
body, head to vivobarefoot.com/doac.
And if you do that, I'll give you 15%
off when you use my code Steven B15.
Use that code at checkout. And I'll also
give you a 100day money back guarantee.
Steven B15.
Enjoy. We have finally caved in. So many
of you have asked us if we could bundle
the conversation cards with the 1%
diary. For those of you that don't know,
every single time a guest sits here with
me in the chair, they leave a question
in the diary of a CEO and then I ask
that question to the next guest. We
don't release those questions in any
environment other than on these
incredible conversation cards. These
have become a fantastic tool for people
in relationships, people in teams, in
big corporations, and also family
members to connect with each other. With
that, we also have the 1% diary, which
is this incredible tool to change habits
in your life. So many of you have asked
if it was possible to buy both at the
same time, especially people in big
companies. So, what we've done is we've
bundled them together and you can buy
both at the same time. And if you want
to drive connection and instill habit
change in your company, head to the
diary.com to inquire and our team will
be in touch. You are very different from
your father. Now listen, I know you you
know you love your father deeply and
I've watched you in every interview
you've ever done to talk to that love
and I have zero exactly zero desire to
to ask you any questions or ask anything
that's going to try and drive a a wedge
or get you to say something that I think
you know is is is not fair. But the
thing I find interesting is that like
how you make your way in the world and
like become your own person
>> when you do have this derivative noise
that's trying to define you through
things that you have never even actually
done.
>> Yeah.
>> And I just find that fascinating like
how and life has clearly made you a
stoic for this very reason because you
have to deal with I guess to some degree
being characterized in a certain way for
actions that you yourself haven't taken.
So one has to become a stoic or else how
could one possibly survive
>> like we all deal I think on microscopic
levels with like
>> the eye of the hurricane.
>> Yeah.
>> I think but like I I sometimes like feel
a lot of gratitude for it because I I
think sometimes you
keep being taught a lesson until you
learn it. And I think as somebody who
always wanted peace and harmony and I
think I needed to like maybe it took
this level of intensity to be like okay
you know like peace and harmony within
the context that I can help facilitate
you know like I can't control something
so much um bigger than that. So so
sometimes like maybe that was my
medicine you know.
>> Did you go to therapy?
not in my childhood in actually as an
adult I um I I have a lot of um friends
who are unbelievable either teachers,
professors, therapists and um and I have
like a very growthoriented mindset as
you could probably tell like I'm always
looking to learn about myself and about
the world and uh so they've provided
unbelievable perspective for me over the
years. I asked that because I imagine
there's lots of people watching now who
contend with their own struggles. Yeah.
>> Similar to that, dealing with the
outside world or
>> I think therapy can be amazing. Um I
think you have to have the right
therapist. Um and somebody who helps you
sort of process and move through. I
don't think it's like healthy to linger
too long. Um like I think you have to
move forward.
>> When did you decide to start seeing a
therapist?
um
in my adulthood like as an adult and it
was more just as like another tool for
me in the same way that I meditate you
know I view it as as an opportunity to
like
to do an internal inventory
>> was there a catalyst there's often a
catalyst when I interview people
something happened they realized that
they needed more tools
>> you know I I think um some of the
challenges es around um Jared's health.
>> I just left Washington. Our life was in
flux. Jared um was diagnosed with
thyroid cancer for a second time. Um and
uh and then my mother passed and I
wanted to make sure I'm I'm really good
at like being tough and I'm really good
at kind of compartmentalizing. So it was
more just like a check with myself that
I was also taking time to like you know
sort of like look inward and uh and like
nurture myself. So it was not it was not
particularly like formal um but it was
more you know and I think when you can
speak to people you trust who are
knowledgeable and just make sure you're
like taking time to like really heal and
not just move forward. You strike me as
someone that spent a lot of time being
tough
>> on the outside.
>> Um because
>> I like tough and super soft at the same
time.
>> But I see that.
>> But I' I've kind of But that's like
where you know I have to like watch
myself from because my life has always
had such intensity like I can like move
through things like I sometimes have to
pull myself back and say like process
because I don't believe that you ever
put something in a box. I think that
thing that you're hiding from yourself
is with you every time you make a bad
decision and like driving the bus, you
know, like it's you may not be like
fully conscious of it, but it's it's
like there so you better unpack it um
and as close to real time as possible, I
think the better.
>> Yeah. And in your context, I imagine as
well, you can't just offload like the
average person does in every context
like Yeah. because there's consequences
to that. Whether it's trusting people,
whether it's the media trying to get
something on you, what, you know,
whoever it might be. So, and then, you
know, you're in a family where,
you know, it's important to keep a
straight face, especially in public a
lot. And I was watching the footage from
>> Yeah. people think I'm like have like
sort of like a stoic look in public. I'm
very like,
>> but I but I spent time with you behind
the scenes. You do you have this sort of
bit of a dichotomy in the sense that
you're there's a real
like pure
um
soft
empathetic
soul. And then it appears to me that
life is
demanded for the survival in the context
you've been in that you pop a mask on in
front of that to keep a straight face
and a tough demeanor and to not punch
back and to to suppress that in certain
contexts because frankly you kind of
have to if you're in the shoes that
you've had to fill. And I guess one can
keep that that mask that tough exterior
on too long.
>> Yeah. Yeah. To the point.
>> Well, I think you actually see it with a
lot of politicians.
They feel inauthentic because they are,
you know, they've experienced so much
that they they never allow the mass to
slip.
>> Yeah.
>> I think one of the things that makes my
father so unique is how is he so
authentic in a world where so few people
are like in that profession, that realm?
And they're like almost like you look at
they feel like they're robots. the way
they speak, the way they interact, the
way they engage. Oftentimes you see that
when you're with them one-on-one as as
you do as it comes across like on a
debate on a television set. Um, so I
think there's a balance. Like I I don't
think you need to be
like your most vulnerable self in the
public. Like why? like what is I think
you want to be authentic but I think
like you should like you have to guard
things about yourself about your family
and I think that's like healthy and and
good and I do think there is a part of
me that's like there's never been like
uh there's no room for error you know
like even as a child like growing up in
the public eye was always nervous about
doing something and embarrassing my
parents and then politics and you have
to be perfect and any slip up is
completely weaponized against you so you
become very careful publicly. I think
the mistake though is people
get confused and they lose a sense of
themselves and
they bring that into their relationships
like off um the public stage and and I
think that's really unfortunate.
>> You mentioned um one of the catalyst
moments for you seeking out some sort of
more professional support was the death
of your mother. 2022.
>> Another beautiful photo of her wonderful
hair as well.
Try not to cry again.
>> It's okay.
>> She's extraordinary.
She was extraordinary.
>> It's okay.
She lived a good life though. You know,
I tell myself with my mom, she like
really lived she had fun. Um, so she
taught me a lot about just like, you
know, the presence I talk about about
just like
bringing intention to what you do.
Bringing Sorry.
Um
she uh
she was very herself and she was very
joyful and she loved to dance and she
loved to play and so um she lived uh she
lived a good life.
It's a really it's a unbelievably tragic
way to lose a parent is suddenly and
unexpected when they are
>> sure
>> strong. I mean it says a lot that your
grandmother which is her mother
>> still alive
>> still alive almost 100 years old and she
lost her life at 70 to falling down the
stairs in her her
>> By the way I said my grandmother was 98
she's 99.
>> Wow. Okay.
>> Crazy. It's amazing.
Yeah. No, it's it very challenging and
you know grief is just
losing a parent. It's it like hits
different you know um especially
unexpectedly especially sort of postco
which like kind of robbed so many of us
of so many years you know some for some
people they
>> sort of sheltered together um and it
actually created connection between
generations and you know unfortunately I
was she was in New York and I was in
Washington so
>> um there was the
there was distance there just
geographically. Um
but um but you know I I really like we
really I was telling you before we
really keep her memory alive like I
really took the time to think about her
not through the eyes of the child who
idolized her fully but through the eyes
of an adult who saw her clearly.
her strengths, her challenges, and like
I think about like my role as a parent
to my own children is
to sort of stand guard against like to
to make sure they're exposed to all the
elements of her that were amazing and
and share the stories and remind them.
Um,
and also to like kind of like a lionist
and guard against the passing on of of
you know challenges she had and and
struggles and um and so I try to do that
with my own family.
>> Have you grieved properly?
>> Yeah,
>> because you're very busy.
>> I think it's no I think it's super
important and that's part of the reason
I really got introspective. I think
wherever there's discomfort, that's
where you have to go.
>> And you know, I would talk about her and
start to cry just like I'm still doing
um but in a different kind of way, you
know, like I I was avoiding
for a moment, a very short moment
because I recognized in myself like the
discomfort and like you have to like
unlock that and you have to really make
the time to think about and talk about
and and process. On the business side of
things, you have started in 2023, I
believe, at 41 years old, you co-founded
Planet Harvest with one of your friends,
Melissa Akerman, inspired by your
experiences creating the USDA's farmers
to families food box program during
COVID 19. When I look at all that you
do, you know, there's you're doing this
incredible project in Albania to develop
the land there. You are investing in
technology companies. you you've got
this planet harvest project with which
is incredible and then you've got you
know um a family which you know you talk
about standing in guard in front of them
and so on and so forth.
How how do you balance all of this
stuff? How does one balance it?
>> You don't like balance is elusive. Like
I think of balance it's like a scale.
It's going to tip. You're one child's
flu away from like complete imbalance,
right? where you get the call from the
school nurse and your son has to come
home unexpectedly or um or there's like
a roadblock in a project you're working
on or you know you can't striving for
balance is not
like a practical pursuit. I think what I
strive for is to live a life that aligns
with my priorities and to have more days
than not that I feel like I've done just
that. And I think if you get that right,
most of the time you're doing pretty
well because balance doesn't work. It's
just like our lives are too hectic and
there's too much outside of our control
to to maintain
that equilibrium.
I'm so curious as to where you've um you
know I know you've read a lot of
stoicism and you read a lot of books and
you've you've been to therapy but you
know you've you contend with a lot
businesses investing the real estate
projects all the family stuff the
broader noise.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and you've really much of what I've
learned about you is that you've really
managed to center yourself on yourself.
>> You've managed to sort of pull yourself
inwards in a world that pulls all of us
outwardly. And is is there a particular
book you might advise people to read
about this or is there or they just have
to have life hit them?
>> Well, I think you know religion for many
people provides a beautiful framework um
whether it's the Bible, the Torah, the
you know of of like be a good person
like really um live a purpose- driven
meaningful life. Um, so I I think
there's so much wisdom there and I I
think, you know, we talked about the
Stoics. I think they're some of the
great guides. I also love some of the
Eastern philosophies. Like I love lu and
the taq ching is an amazing it kind of
reminds me of like the it was like
similar to the philosophy of of jiujitsu
around just sort of presence and and not
sort of fighting what is you know so
much of suffering comes from a rejection
of like what is um like fighting
something that it just is fact um as
opposed to sort of that which is within
our control. So I I'm actually very
drawn to sort of Buddhism and Dowoism
and um I personally feel um like very
alive. Like I think
you look at if you if you think back
over the last week and I don't know what
this is for you but you think back over
the last week maybe even the last month
or the last day like when you were in
like a flow state when you fel felt most
alive like that's your medicine like
that's like you in your essence. But so
I try to also like put myself in those
situations as much as possible and and
um and make sure to like bring that into
my life.
>> I'm fascinated by Planet Harvest
>> because you could have done so much with
the leverage and and experience that you
have and you chose to build a business
called Planet Harvest, which you can
find at planeth harvest.com that is
helping to reduce food waste and
creating change for farmers across the
country. why of all the things that you
could have aimed at um and I know you're
aiming at many at once, but why is
Planet Harvest so central to your
mission at the moment?
>> Thank you. I mean, this is truly like a
missiondriven
um passion and and pursuit of mine and
um I think I told you before that like
there's nothing better than
being obvious by being contrarian. And
and that's sort of how Planet Harvest
was born. saw through the co pandemic.
Um, I got really close to the farmers
because I created this farmertof family
food box program that created grants
that would enable farmers to sell their
perishable produce um to third parties,
distributors, NOS's, churches who would
then get it to the last mile of needs,
ensuring that when people needed food,
the food in the fields wasn't going to
waste by being tilled under as we saw in
the early days of the pandemic. You
know, the supply chain shut down. So the
restaurants were closed, the airlines,
the hotels. Um, so the farmers had no
place to to send their food and couldn't
afford to take it out of the fields. So
we created a grant program to enable
that connection. But it really got me um
very close at a at a farm level to to
the farmer and and and their experience.
And obviously that was a catastrophic
time when there was just zero demand.
But but I started seeing even in a
normalized situation the amount of waste
that happens on a food on a on a field
level and the amount of food beautiful
nutritious perfect food that's left to
rot in the fields while so many
communities want for for that form of
nutrition. and um and I I met a woman um
who's uh CEO of the company and we
decided to co-found an effort together
to utilize this excess and create demand
for it and and get it into the ecosystem
supporting the environment, supporting
um these great American farmers. Like
I'll just give you one example. I mean,
strawberries,
400 million pounds of strawberries every
year get left in the fields, not even
taken out and and given. Not because
they're imperfect. They're just don't
meet a really rigid
cosmetic specification that's defined by
retailers oftent times 20, 30, 40 years
ago so that everything's very
standardized. It's just a great way to
solve a problem, provide incremental
revenue for farmers, which is so needed
in such a tough business. So, we're
really proud of of the work we're doing
there.
>> It's a beautiful, beautiful cause. I'm
going to link link below if anyone wants
to learn more um as many details as they
can about the project and ways others
can get involved, whether they're
retailers or farmers or anyone that's
interested in getting involved. Um,
Avanka, we have a closing tradition
where the last guest leaves a question
for the next guest, not knowing who
they're leaving it for. And the question
that has been left for you, it assumes
you are a parent, so thankfully you are,
um, is if your oldest child came to you
and said they wanted to follow in your
footsteps, what are the three pieces of
advice you would give them that would
increase their probability of happiness
and success?
>> Oh, that's a great question. Um,
I think first and foremost,
>> that's your eldest.
>> Yes.
>> Arabella, is it?
>> Arabella.
So what would you say to Arabella? She
says she wants to be an entrepreneur and
an investor. And
>> I think first you have to love it.
I think especially if you want to be an
entrepreneur like the amount of work and
dedication and grind, the challenges,
um the responsibility as you build a
business for other people's livelihoods.
Um it's it's enormous and it's you know
this I mean it's it's it can be very
heavy um to carry and I have never seen
someone
at the peak of their game who doesn't
absolutely love what they do and I've
seen a lot of brilliant people I went to
school with many of them who were way
smarter
>> than anyone else in the class who flamed
out
>> by going in a direction that they were
capable and proficient
but not passionate about. So, it has to
you have to want it because if you
don't, somebody who's less um perhaps
less capable, perhaps less smart,
they'll work twice as hard and like you
can't compete with that.
>> Mhm.
>> So, that's number one. I think number
two
is um
you can't imitate anyone. You have to be
yourself. And we've talked a lot about
like knowing thyself, but um actually uh
Naval who's a friend of mine who's who's
great um he talks about like as an
entrepreneur the importance of
authenticity and how
it's like it's the key like when you're
copying you're losing like you have to
be yourself and then nobody can compete
with you. Um, and so I think you you
have to sort of find yourself, be
yourself. You can't be derivative of
anything else. Of course, you can learn
from others, but um, but you have to
blaze your own course and um, and as an
entrepreneur building something new, you
have to have also like a tremendous
amount of resilience through that
process.
And
you know it's um that's nuanced in and
of itself because that doesn't mean like
you have to wear blinders and go when
you know it's right but you have to also
I mean they talk about the famous pivot
right like in like you also have to
pivot sometimes right so it's not not
like a fault you have to still be
receptive to um to sort of incoming
information but for the most part like
you have to go and um and I think for a
young person I would tell my daughter,
you know, you're going to have to
believe in yourself before the world
believes in you. Like, you can't wait
for the world to believe in you
>> because if you haven't believed in
yourself, you'll never get there. So,
you have to start. And that's why like I
love talking like one of the things I've
I've been doing a lot of is investing in
technology businesses, AI, robotics, um,
incredible founders and entrepreneurs
doing building generationally defining
products.
um and and developing these amazing
ideas and I love seeing the belief and
the conviction they have in themselves
and sometimes like it's like their
experience doesn't match like their
confidence but like you have to start
somewhere and if you don't like believe
in yourself you'll never get out of the
gate. So, so believe in yourself,
charge forward, and um and then when you
start putting up some W's and getting
some wins, like the rest of the world
may or may not um start to believe in
you as well,
>> thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> YouTube have this new crazy algorithm
where they know exactly what video you
would like to watch next based on AI and
all of your viewing behavior. And the
algorithm says that this video is the
perfect video for you. It's different
for everybody looking right now.